- ♪ In the not-too-distant
Future ♪
♪ Next Sunday AD ♪
♪ There was a guy named Joel ♪
♪ Not too different
From you or me ♪
♪ He worked at
Gizmonic Institute ♪
♪ Just another face
In a red jumpsuit ♪
♪ He did a good job
Cleaning up the place ♪
♪ But his bosses
Didn't like him ♪
♪ So they shot him into space ♪
♪ We'll send him
Cheesy movies ♪
♪ The worst we can find
La-la-la ♪
♪ He'll have to sit
And watch them all ♪
♪ And we'll monitor his mind
La-la-la ♪
♪ Now keep in mind
Joel can't control ♪
♪ Where the movies begin or end
La-la-la ♪
♪ Because he used
Those special parts ♪
♪ To make his
Robot friends ♪
- Robot Roll Call:
All right, let's go!
- Cambot!
- Pan left!
- Gypsy!
- Hi, girl!
- Tom Servo!
- What a cool guy!
- Croooow!
- He's a wisecracker.
- ♪ If you're wondering
How he eats and breathes ♪
♪ A nd other science facts
La la la ♪
♪ Then repeat to yourself
It's just a show ♪
♪ I should really just relax ♪
♪ For Mystery Science
Theater 3000! ♪
- Woo, whoop, woo, whoop.
- It's a super party here
on the Satellite of Love.
Me and my robots
are having
kind of an orbiting
root beer kegger.
- Oh yeah.
- Oh, hi, go!
- Woo-hoo.
- Uh, hey guys...
uh, looks like
the keg's fried.
- Boo.
- Bummer!
- Wow, this is far from
industrial, man!
- Listen, you guys.
There's a lot you can do
even when the keg
has run out.
Now, oh my God,
like pin the flames on Gamera,
and we got this Gamera pinata.
- Right!
- There's just a lot of stuff
you can do.
- Everybody quiet!
I just want to say
that Joel Robinson
is one fine human being.
Commercial sign-off.
- Enough for you.
- Uh-hm.
[♪♪♪]
[SHOUTING, CHEERING]
- Oh, yuk! Oh, yuk!
- We got to make a new bunch
of this!
- Oh man, [indistinct].
- Hey, hey.
Mellow out, you guys.
This is a call.
Might be my parents. Be quiet!
- This guy had guts like that.
One time I was out...
- Crow, lighten up.
This could be my parents.
- Oh, sorry, dude.
Didn't mean to keep going...
- Cut it out up there.
The Satellite of Love
is not a party machine.
- I don't know what you folks
are doing up there,
but if I were you,
I'd take the pizza
off the ceiling.
- Well, mere peoples,
our invention exchange this week
is a new consumer product.
Fra-a-a-nk.
- Hi.
My name is TV's Frank,
and I am a stoogeaholic.
- Hi, TV's Frank.
- You know, ever since
I was a little kid,
I was always
a big Three Stooges fan
in all their various
incarnations,
except for Curly Joe DeRita.
You know,
he lacked subtlety.
But you know,
I could never emulate
their exquisite
fight choreography...
until now, that is.
- That's right.
That's why we've invented these,
the Three Stooges gun.
They come in both
offensive and defensive...
Hey, spinach chin!
- No, Moe!
Nyuk nyuk nyuk!
Whoop! Whoop!
- Oh, how I loathe you!
- Certainly.
Whoop! Whoop!
- Joel, Joel! JOEL!
Ugh!
- Oh, sorry!
Sorry, sirs.
Oh, well, my invention
this week is kind of based
on something I invented
during the party.
You know, how I took
Tom Servo and turned him
into a root beer
pony keg here...
I thought
I could do the same
kind of thing
with Crow the Robot.
I've actually...
Crow, would you
come over here please?
CROW:
I'm not coming out.
- Crow, come on.
- How exciting!
What a delicious,
what a delicious...
- I feel so ridiculous!
- I figured I could take Crow,
TV's Crow, the loveable,
wisecracking robot,
and turn him into
a delicious shish-kebab.
You know, robots after all,
are made out of metal.
They can withstand great heat.
Earlier today, I baked
a duplicate Crow at 500 degrees.
- Oh, you'll appreciate...
- Don't say anything.
- It just looks so delicious.
- And he'll end up looking
just like this
when he's done.
- Oh boy,
if food could talk,
I wonder what this
delicious dish would say.
- Bite me!
- What do you think, sirs?
- Brace yourself, Jeff Smith.
I've been waiting all week
for the sadistic pleasure
I'm going to get
when I tell you
that the experiment this week...
- It's Gamera versus Zigra.
We know already.
That's why
we're having this party.
It's our last Gamera movie.
- How did you find out?
Who ruined my surprise?
ALL:
Frank told us.
- Frank!
Doh, ugh.
FRANK:
Ooooh, owie,
owie, owie, owie...
- This may be your last
Gamera film,
but there's no guarantee
you're going to survive it.
Party's over, Frank!
ALL:
Oh no, we've got movie silence.
Let's get outta here!
JOEL:
Sounds like it's
Gamera versus Zig...
oh, we know, yeah.
- Oh, yeah.
TOM SERVO:
It does sound like
the Monster Song [indistinct]
JOEL:
The "Monster Go Home" theme,
yeah.
- [indistinct]
JOEL:
Hidemasa in
the cold, cold ground.
TOM SERVO:
Um, Steven Foster,
oh, and Fumi here,
he's the John Sayles of Japan.
He directed "The Return of
the Secaucus Seven Samurai",
whoo, whoo.
I love him.
Tonight on Yuasa network,
"Swamp Thing".
- Do not bring your evil here!
TOM SERVO:
You hear that?
A little bassoon sound there.
- I could do that.
[CROW MAKES RASPBERRY SOUNDS]
JOEL:
Oh!
CROW:
How rude!
[CROW MAKES RASPBERRY SOUNDS]
JOEL:
Oh, come on.
TOM SERVO:
Isn't it fun?
JOEL:
I didn't know you had
any fleshy parts to do that.
CROW:
Well, I really don't.
Oh, what was that?
[SHRILL]
- Oh, oh.
Ow, ow.
JOEL:
That burned.
Kikuchi, kikuchi.
- Kikuchi, [indistinct]
JOEL:
Hey look,
they got funny Japanese names.
Ha, ha.
- Ha, ha, huh.
[SHRILL]
- Ow.
- What happened?
- Don't know.
Something kind of...
JOEL:
Ow!
TOM SERVO:
What is that anyway?
JOEL:
Oooh, ahh, no.
TOM SERVO:
Synthetic mosquitoes.
JOEL:
Both Zoellner sisters
in one film... oh wow!
TOM SERVO: Beautiful.
- In color.
NARRATOR:
Since the dawn of time,
man's most cherished dream
was to fly to the moon.
TOM SERVO:
No, it's gonna
be a Michener story.
NARRATOR:
...of the 20th century,
that age-old dream
suddenly became a reality.
TOM SERVO:
Broadway!
NARRATOR:
Inaugurating
the extraordinary age
of cosmic exploration.
JOEL:
I didn't know the moon
was made of rich,
gooey chocolate.
NARRATOR:
All the great nations
of the world...
JOEL:
It's carob.
NARRATOR:
...cooperated and developed
new forms of energy
and aircraft
in the exciting race
for the conquest of space.
- Oh, and believe me,
it's exciting.
- How can you not think
this is exciting.
[CHUCKLES]
NARRATOR:
But that first great leap
for mankind...
Soon became an alarming danger
- Uh, oooo...
NARRATOR:
...as peaceful
scientific discoveries
and inventions were turned
into terrifying
weapons of destruction.
JOEL:
Oh, blame it on us.
NARRATOR:
...on other galaxies
invaded our own universe.
CROW:
The invaders in... oh, sorry.
NARRATOR:
Most terrifying of all
was Zigra,
a seemingly invincible enemy
from a world
many light years away,
bent on
plundering and destroying
everything in his path.
TOM SERVO:
Oh, like Al Sharpton.
NARRATOR:
...enslaving all of mankind.
JOEL:
Was that necessary?
- Uh-hm, ahem.
You have got to be kidding me!
JOEL:
We can see the glue.
[CHUCKLES]
- Models by
Eric and Louis Grunden,
4th and 5th grade,
Mrs. Johnson's class.
TOM SERVO:
That big daddy rocks! Whoa!
- Oh no, the stretching beam.
You blurred me!
- Uh-hm.
JOEL:
So much for cosmic exploration.
CROW:
It was a blast!
NARRATOR:
Sea World,
the international
marine life center.
- Sushi lovers go
straight to the source.
- How's your wife, Tom?
- What's that
supposed to mean?
- Yeah, the new baby's
coming in a week or so.
- Well, I suppose
you'd like a boy this time.
- What do you mean by that?
- [indistinct]
[LAUGHS]
CROW:
Jerk!
- I hope we're not spoiling
your sister's summer vacation.
- What about my sister?
- She's happy to do
a little extra work
and earn some money,
but I'm not sure
she can handle Margie and Helen.
- Hm, I don't know either.
Those daughters of mine
are no angels.
JOEL:
Let's go get some
tuna-safe dolphin.
- Helen, it's time to wake up
or you'll be late for school.
- I'd better take
your restraints off.
- Margie, wake up.
Hurry now.
JOEL:
They are youth in Asia.
TOM SERVO:
I don't believe you said that!
- Well, do as you want.
- I'm the mischievous one.
- Stop watching TV
and brush your teeth.
And do it properly
this morning, you hear?
JOEL:
No more fish paste and sea weed,
please, Mom.
- Don't you want to have
nice shiny white teeth?
The Sea World animals
do it a lot better than you.
- Huh?
- These Sea World whales
were brought here
all the way from Canada
last year.
- Uh-hm, uh-hm, uh-hm.
- ...is 10 months old.
The other one, Chippie,
is a female.
- Hurry, or you're going to be
late for school again.
- Oh!
- Oh, look at you.
Will you wash
that whipped cream off.
Even the killer whales
rinse their mouths.
- Killer whales spit take.
[LAUGHTER]
- Are his teeth
in good condition.
Would you take a look?
- Sure.
- [indistinct] the killer
whales here at Sea World and...
- Okay, bite down.
- Oooh.
- You know you must take
good care of your teeth
or the dolphins
will make fun of you.
- And Daddy won't love you.
- Uh-hm.
- Margie, Helen.
You forgot something, wait.
Your mother's
in a hospital in New York...
- Detoxing.
-...and you both forgot
to kiss her good-bye.
Go on, send your mother
a big kiss.
- Uh, so when do you
get off work anyway.
Uh-ha-uh-ha.
[PANTING]
- ...and say good-bye
to everyone now.
Have a nice rest.
We want you to...
- Hey, they're
getting' hammered.
What's goin' on?
- ...next show at 2 o'clock
this afternoon.
Good-bye now.
- Bye.
- Good morning, Kenny.
- Good morning, Margie,
Good morning, Helen.
JOEL: Where's your hat?
- How's it going?
- Never a dull moment.
[LAUGHTER]
- ...in the jungle
and have adventure...
JOEL:
Just like the Goonies.
- Now you two be good
and do everything
the teacher tells you,
and you'll be
clever little children.
As clever as the dolphins.
- Stop, I hear that all
the time from my own parents.
- If you want me
to be like a dolphin,
I'll have to learn
to swim first.
- You'll have to learn
to blow air
out of the back
of your neck too.
- ...and now for some
morning exercises.
Jumbo is showing off
standing on his head.
- Jumbo?
- ...while
Sabu does a handstand.
Now you mustn't
applaud yourself...
[LAUGHTER]
...would rather see
how well you play basketball.
I heard that you're
a regular champion.
Noro has the ball and he's
going to try to score a point.
Will he succeed?
TOM SERVO:
Nice hat.
- Bravo.
How about giving him a hand,
ladies and gentlemen?
That's Noco,
our older lady seal,
proving diving
isn't just a male sport.
Good girl!
And now, a swimming race.
A real Olympic contest.
JOEL:
Aw, all the Canadian seals
are on steroids.
- ...seems to be gaining.
No, it's Noro followed
by Sabu and Noco,
and Noro wins,
so Noro gets the gold medal.
- Uh-oh. He gives
the black power salute
and is stripped of his medal.
- and our charming Noco
gets the bronze
and peanuts for the others.
- Peanuts?
- Oh, and that's their reward?
Getting stuffed?
- Do you mean
that you have to dissect her
to find out why she died?
- That's right.
We have to discover
what caused her death
to protect
the other animals.
- Then she goes up
on my office wall.
- Mr. Yamoto,
we know you treated them
exactly like your children,
so we understand
how you feel.
- Indifferent?
[LAUGHS]
[♪♪♪]
- Kathryn...
have you seen Helen?
She hasn't come back yet.
- No, she was playing
with Kenny awhile ago.
- Honey, time for a new apron.
- Uh-hm.
- They left their things here.
- And they didn't
separate their colors.
- Things appear
and disappear like magic.
- They sure do!
[LAUGHTER]
- Oh, Heathcliff.
- Wuthering Heights.
- Babe Winkelman.
- Hm.
- If things go on like this,
the whole coastline
will be polluted.
- Yeah, nothing
can live in this.
There won't be a fish left
in a few years.
- Maybe dolphins.
- ...it would be our own fault.
- Science always
seem to destroy nature
instead of doing
everything to protect it.
It's up to biologists like us
to warn the world
what's happening around us.
- Yeah, save the message
for the end of the movie.
- We bring you a special news
announcement.
A special news announcement.
At 9 AM today,
there was a major earthquake
in the Indian Ocean.
- Hm.
- Ten thousand people died
and hundreds of thousands
were injured.
The force of the earthquake
was one of the greatest
ever recorded.
Magnitude 16...
- I'm going to the top
of the [indistinct].
- ...more powerful than the one
that rocked Peru yesterday.
I repeat, today at 9 AM,
there was...
- One earthquake
right after the other.
It's awful.
- Did you hear?
A force of magnitude 16 is,
and on opposite sides
of the earth.
- Hm.
- Incredible, isn't it?
- Very strange.
- No more than
those stretch pants.
- Time for a little snack.
- Okay.
- Uh-hm.
- Kathryn prepared one of her
specialties, lemonade...
- ...and I've got your
sister's specialty,
peanut butter sandwiches.
- Hey, hey...
- You leave my sister
out of this. Shut up.
Take it back, take it back,
you rotten, crummy...
- Uh-oh.
- Hey, my jigger of gin
is empty.
- My sister forgot
the sandwiches.
- Naw, I saw her put them in.
- And I saw Kathryn fill this.
- What happened then?
- Maybe your sister ate them.
- Shut up about my sister,
shut up.
- [indistinct] pitchfork.
- Aha.
- I don't feel well.
I think I ate too much.
Have you got any medicine?
- I want a Coke, Daddy.
- Kenny, didn't I tell you
not to come here
without permission?
- Helen, when we get home,
you'll get a nice spanking.
- Can I have it now?
- What's that?
What's that thing over there?
- Kenny, now don't try to
change the subject.
- Look, look at that,
in the sky.
TOM SERVO:
See it? Um.
JOEL:
Maybe they have sandwiches.
- Strange looking.
- It could be an artificial
satellite that's fallen.
JOEL:
Maybe it's a HoJos.
- ...or else
a kind of space station.
- Well, whatever it is,
we can't afford to
show it [indistinct].
- Meanwhile, at Dollyworld...
- Outside is
an unidentified object.
It was first seen off the coast
of Kanagawa City.
- Five miles from Cucamonga.
- ...[indistinct] to the sea.
Latitude 34-40 NW,
longitude 140-20 SW.
- Henry.
- Portrait of a serial killer.
- You know the waters
are deep there,
and it's the dolphin's
favorite spot.
- Hm.
- It would be tragic
if they got hurt.
- Tom, shall we look?
- Sure.
- Hmm.
- But what about the kids?
- I'll go too,
after all I am the son
of a marine life biologist.
- And I wanna go too, Daddy.
- Okay, okay.
You collaborators.
- Yeah, maybe they have
Coke out there, kid.
- Hey, look,
it's Fredo Corleone. Huh.
Pitshu!
ALL:
♪ Casper the friendly ghost ♪
- Shhh!
- And Little Audrey says...
- This is terrific!
- Hey, it's just a boat,
come on.
- Hey, look, Dots,
jelly beans, Skittles,
Gummi Bears, Jujubes. Umm!
- Piles!
- Hey, who roached?
- M&Ms, melt underwater,
not in your hand.
- Uh?
- Gamera!
- Please welcome your host
and emcee
from Monsterland in Miami Beach,
Gamera!
- Gamera's here!
- I don't like monsters.
- Gamera is the friend
of all children.
- Is he, really?
- Yeah,
if you get on his good side,
but don't cross him.
[MONSTER ROARS]
- You know what's weird,
but even the monster's
badly dubbed.
- Yeah.
- ...he answers.
- Monsters can't talk.
- You read too much!
- Ha, ha, he's lapping them.
- Cool.
- Uh-oh.
- Hey, who runs
the flying saucer?
Timothy William?
- Uh-oh, I'm outta here.
I'm going home.
Uh-hm.
[MONSTER ROARS]
- What, what?
ZIGRA WOMAN:
I have obeyed your orders,
Zigra.
I have brought
the earth creatures to you.
ZIGRA:
Good work.
I am pleased...
- As punch.
ZIGRA:
Now, awaken them.
- Pay no attention to the man
behind the curtain.
ZIGRA WOMAN:
Yes, Zigra. Creatures of
the earth, wake up!
- You know, it looks
kind like the Hullabaloo set
except for that monster.
- That looks like
a Judy Chicago sculpture.
- Uh-hm.
- Yeah, it looks the crazy
Guggenheim Museum.
- Uh-hm.
- Where are we?
- I know.
We're inside a spaceship.
- And she's a space woman.
- I know!
- You two watch television
too much.
- Say what you want, Dad...
ZIGRA WOMAN:
The two children
have understood
the situation correctly.
Earth creatures,
welcome to
the Zigra star spaceship.
- Oh, it's Grace Slick.
- Zigra star spaceship,
huh, that's ridiculous!
I've never heard
that name before.
ZIGRA WOMAN:
You will hear it very often
from now on.
- 'Cause I repeat things a lot.
- Sorry, all we have
is a master shop for this scene.
- Yeah, who filmed this,
Jim Jarmusch?
[CHUCKLES]
- She's hot, Dad.
- Shhh, shhh.
- When we get back, not a word
of this to your mother, kids.
- We come from a planet located
in the Romulus galaxy,
sector Ford.
- Oh, the Ford Galaxy!
- Our celestial body #105.
- I know!
- The distance
between our planet
and earth is 400 light years.
- Four hundred light years?
I don't believe it!
- Why, even if you could travel
at the speed of light,
it would take you
400 years to get here.
It's illogical.
- What, is this logical?
- You forget space is curved.
- And so am I!
- I doubt your earthly vanity
prevents you from believing
that there are higher forms
of civilization than you.
- But, even so,
no one could...
- Oh really?
Explain how your boat got here
or did you swim
through the fourth dimension?
- You're right, I'm ashamed.
Spank me.
- I told you.
She's a space woman.
And she has
super-celestial powers.
- I knew it, too.
I bet she can even do magic.
- Children grasp things
much faster than adults.
Their innocence
makes them see things clearly.
- Just the same,
it's hard to believe.
- Yes, and what's your purpose
in bringing us here.
- Zigrans have attained
the highest culture ever known--
- Yogurt.
- ...and we want you
to tell the world
about all our great
achievements in science.
Do you agree
to do that for us?
- Now please
take off the Bob Hope hat.
- All right.
Prove to us that you are
from the planet Zigra,
show us your scientific skills,
and when we're on Earth,
we'll report what we see.
- Very well.
I knew you would cooperate.
- Hm. Heh.
- Now, allow me to show you.
- My anti-cellulite machine.
- That reminds me,
I must get my watch fixed.
- Special effects
by Soupy Sales.
- Time for
At-Home with Pink Lady.
[STATIC ON RADIO]
- All you people of the Earth...
all you people of the Earth.
- Why do you
zombies hide your faces?
ZIGRA WOMAN:
I am a representative
of the great planet Zigra,
celestial body #105,
sector four.
- I know.
ZIGRA WOMAN:
I am going to cause
an earthquake in Tokyo
that you never thought possible.
An earthquake of magnitude 18,
greater than
the recent earthquakes
in Peru and the Indian Ocean.
- Are you thinking
what I'm thinking?
- Furthermore, I'll prove to you
the strength
of our great science.
I shall cause
the greatest earthquake
the world has ever witnessed.
It will destroy everything...
all Tokyo
will be annihilated in a minute.
- Wow, she's PMSing big time.
- Uh-hm.
- You, you're crazy.
You're out of your mind.
- Just see what I can do!
- Hey, hey focus.
- You will not call me crazy
after this...
- Hey, focus, focus. Hey.
- ...the greatest earthquake,
magnitude 18 no less.
- Hm?
- Papa, what's magnitude mean?
- I think it means green.
- It's the force of the
earthquake on a certain scale.
You see,
they calculate the shockwaves
to the center of the earth.
The amplitude
is measured in micron units
and the intensity recorded
is the magnitude, understand?
- Dad, I'm six!
- Hm, hm, hm.
- The Great Kanto earthquake
was only magnitude 11-1/2.
- Oh, the
Great Kanto earthquake, hm...
- Even your earthquake
off San Rico Island
was only
about magnitude 13-1/2...
- Which is also
the IQ of Sandy Frank.
- No, don't.
You mustn't go ahead with it.
Stop it, please!
- Too late.
No one can stop it any longer.
The vibration generator
has been started already.
- There's no point to the...
- Senseless killing...
JOEL:
Now, wait a minute,
wait a minute.
Let me get this straight.
This model is gonna
teach me how Gamera works?
- Yup!
- It's gonna teach me
how he shoots flames out
and flies around?
- Ye-up!
- It's gonna teach me
how he breathes underwater?
- For sure!
- It's gonna teach me
how he does gymnastics?
TOM SERVO and CROW:
Just open the shell, Doofus.
- Ta-da! Welcome to Gamera,
the biggest, friendliest
super turtle there ever was.
- Wow, you guys
made this yourself.
That's pretty great.
- Our tour starts here
at the monster's head.
Down the grand
spiral staircase
which leads to the galley
where Gamera keeps
all his favorite refreshments
and cheesy comestibles.
- Whoa.
Just a technical question.
When Gamera brings his head in,
what happens
to this big cast iron
spiral staircase.
- Oh, that's a special
spring steel stairway.
It collapses
when Gamera pulls his head in.
Resuming our tour...
- Stay with the group, Joel.
CROW:
Below the galley is Kenny's room
for when he sleeps over.
[TOM SERVO MAKING SOUNDS]
It's filled with mementos
of all the terrific adventures
that Gamera and Kenny
have had over the years.
He also has one of those
special little refrigerators
filled with ice cold Snickers,
Milky Way
and Three Musketeers bars.
- Oh, well, what's this room
down here?
- Oh, that's apartment 4B
where the lonely cat man lives.
Below that is the boiler room
filled with highly schooled
robots or thinking machines
and each do the work of 10 men
and each make over $100
[indistinct] credits a day.
- Great, wow.
What's this over here then?
- Oh, that's for your men,
and those little costumes
are for when Kenny
has half the day off
from school.
He can come over to Gamera
and dress up.
There's a Rat Patrol hat
and official Packer uniform
with a helmet and one
World Federation Wrestling belt
and just about a jillion
other costumes as well.
Each one's as important
as the other ones I mentioned
and worth over $100.
- Wow. What about this?
Looks kind of like
some catacombs or something.
- Oh, that's the part
I came up with.
I took the liberty of converting
Gamera's intestines
into a super-cool wine cellar
and make-out cavern.
So whenever Kenny's in bed,
Gamera can have a lovely,
mature woman
over for some laughs
and some love.
- And what's this down here?
- His pooper or his anus,
that's the correct medical word.
Do, do, do...
- Oh, uh, it's just
a dimensional model of Gamera.
You should really just relax.
- Oh, what about this?
- To our left, you'll notice
Gamera's game room.
Oh, he's got a jukebox
with classic rock 45s,
a vintage Madam LaRue
pinball game that he's converted
so you don't
have to use a quarter.
Oh, and just a lot of other
great stuff too
that you'd really love to have
and Jesus lives there.
- Wow. What about this?
- Oh, that's their little oven
to breathe underwater,
shoot flames
and do gymnastics.
But whatever you do,
don't open that door, Joel,
no, no, no, no...
- No, no, please, Mr. Joel,
don't open that door.
Don't throw me
in the briar patch.
- Oh, so what could possibly
be behind this door.
CROW and TOM SERVO:
His guts...see.
[♪♪♪]
JOEL:
Uh-hm, that was funny
with the guts.
CROW:
Sorry about the mess.
TOM SERVO:
On your left, the movie.
- This is a famous hotel
in the center of the city.
CROW:
Home of the Algonquin
Round Table. Hm.
- And this is
the business district.
JOEL:
Oh, now there's
even less parking!
- It's barbaric!
- Savage!
- It lacks subtlety.
- And here's the expressway.
Now you see the extent
of our power and science.
TOM SERVO:
We'll have to take
alternate routes.
- Zigra, why did you
cause that earthquake.
It's sheer madness.
TOM SERVO:
"Cause I didn't
make the cheerleading squad".
- All you earth creatures,
you must surrender at once.
We on Zigra planet,
we used to live in the sea...
JOEL:
But then WE got a job!
ZIGRA WOMAN:
Your earth science
polluted the water,
and we could
no longer live there.
[ALL GULP]
So we studied the other planets
to find water
where we could survive...
JOEL:
And then we struck
like Yul Brenner in
"The King and I".
ZIGRA WOMAN:
We went as far as
Remus Galaxy...
- Uncle Remus?
ZIGRA WOMAN:
Finally one day,
we found an ideal planet
sufficient for all our needs.
TOM SERVO:
Right on the bus line.
- It is your Earth
where 70% of the surface
is covered by the oceans.
But, even your seas and oceans
are becoming polluted.
All covered with slime...
- Kinda looks like
Callahan Harbor.
- ...oil slicks,
filth of all sorts,
making it unfit
for any kind of life.
- [indistinct] watery.
ZIGRA WOMAN:
If we leave the Earth to you,
it will soon be a dead planet.
- Doo, doo, doo, doot.
- Uh, message
coming for you sir. Message.
- Creatures of the Earth,
you must surrender at once.
Creatures of the Earth,
henceforth the Earth
shall be our colony.
We shall take control
of all the oceans.
TOM SERVO:
What a wet blanket!
CROW:
Uh-hm.
- We shall be your masters.
You've seen
the extent of our power.
It is useless for you
to attempt to defy us.
You talk to them!
- Duh, me?
No, I don't I can 'cause
I can't [indistinct] crowds.
- Take the Bob Hope
hat off first.
- Ergh, um, um.
- You people on Earth,
I work at the International
Marine Life Center...
- And you don't, ha, ha.
- And the water
is polluted on our planet.
Every day the situation
is getting worse.
- She's crazy!
I tell you she's crazy!
- The look of lo-o-ve.
- Eh, eh, he,
but did I say crazy?
I meant in a nice way,
I, oh, oh... ouch!
- Tom, what is it?
What have you done?
- The adults bought it.
We're on our own!
- Be careful, Helen.
Don't look into her eyes!
- Okay.
- Don't look
at the [indistinct].
- Come here, come here, I said!
- Oh, check this out.
She can rule the world,
but she can't run in heels.
Huh, huh.
TOM SERVO: Hard to do.
CROW:
Yeah, you're right.
- Look, she stopped moving.
HELEN:
Let's get out of here.
- All right,
only which way do we go?
HELEN:
Let's try the opposite way
we came in here.
- Okay.
TOM SERVO:
Good thinking, 99.
KENNY:
Father, let's go, let's go!
HELEN: He's walking.
KENNY: Come on!
- Grab your dad, come on.
- You too, Daddy, wake up!
- Come on dummy!
- Let's get back into the boat!
Come on, I'm going to sail it
right out of here.
- It's not moving!
- We're little kids.
I didn't say we're smart.
- Press that green button there.
- Okay.
- Did they get that boat
in the back of a comic book?
- Hurry, hurry.
TOM SERVO:
I think the kid
just ordered a key lime pie.
JOEL:
Oh, I saw this
on a David Copperfield special.
- Dead calm.
- Heh, it's Shelly Winters
and Montgomery Clift.
It... um...
- Dad, you see, I did dit!
- Well, my Daddy said
it always pays to try.
- Yeah.
- Papa.
Try to wake up.
- Daddy, wake up.
BOTH:
Wake up!
- What's wrong?
- They're sleeping
because they've been
hypnotized.
We have to leave them
here like that now.
CROW:
Over the side with them. Argh!
- Can we get away
from here, Kenny?
- Okay, I'll see if I can
get the motor working.
- Uh, just let me work out
for a few years, bulk up.
- Kenny, keep on trying.
- I am trying.
The spaceship was easy,
but the motor [indistinct]
working is much harder.
CROW:
Spotlight on evil girl.
ZIGRA:
Follow those children,
and kill them!
- Yes, Master.
- And maybe you could
dust up here sometime.
ZIGRA:
They know too much about us
and this spaceship.
- Yuk!
ZIGRA:
And our secret plans
to conquer the Earth
and make it our colony.
You must find them
and kill them.
- Blah, blah, blah.
- You must sink the Bismarck!
- I have understood, Master.
I shall kill them both
and then I'll also destroy
the entire population.
ZIGRA:
No, do not kill the people.
It would be
a very foolish mistake.
On Earth,
the people live on land.
- Oh, Mrs. Rittenhouse...
- Hmph.
ZIGRA:
But it is just the opposite
with us.
We live in the sea,
and eat things living on land.
ALL:
It's a switcheroo!
ZIGRA:
At present, the Earth people
have large stocks of food
on their dock
and in their warehouses...
- I want Mrs. Paul dead!
ZIGRA:
So you see it would be unwise
to kill the Earth creatures.
- Eew, somebody flush!
ZIGRA:
We must conquer them.
Let them live
so they can become our slaves.
ZIGRA WOMAN:
I understand, Master Zigra.
ZIGRA:
Good.
So follow the children...
and kill...
- And bless the beasts.
ZIGRA:
...only those two.
Is that clear?
- Yes.
TOM SERVO:
But take all you kill.
CROW:
So now it's a scene
from "Ordinary People".
JOEL:
Iwo Jima babies from Jim Hensen.
- Ah, there's a ship
over there...
Could we go to it?
- Um, I'm afraid not.
- Hurry or else
we'll get caught again!
ALL:
Uh?
TOM SERVO:
African Queen babies.
[LAUGHS]
- What?
[IN UNISON]:
Uh-uh.
JOEL:
It's the attack
of the Sydney Opera House.
CROW:
Oh, oh, here he comes again
and Pavaroti's playing tonight.
- Look, it's heading
right at us!
TOM SERVO:
Oh Kenny, my life's
right before my eyes...
diapers, toilet training.
Please [indistinct].
That's it.
- Daddy, Daddy.
- Help us, help us!
JOEL:
Where's Papa?
- Starring Ruth Gordon.
- Uh-hm.
ALL:
Daddy, [indistinct] Daddy.
Save us, Daddy.
- Hmpf.
TOM SERVO:
Kept these kids
kind of gamey anyway.
JOEL:
Yeah, stringy.
HELEN:
Oh, he's turning around!
[♪♪♪]
- It's coming back.
- Look, Kenny.
Up there.
- Gamera!
CROW:
What do you know!
JOEL:
Hey, bring it in Gamera.
Hey, this didn't happen in Jaws.
- Cool.
- Gamera save us!
- Gamera, help, help,
we are here.
- Hey.
- Yeah.
JOEL:
It's a Gene Simmons impression.
TOM SERVO:
The actress?
CROW:
Nice tongue, huh?
TOM SERVO:
Hey, how do you like
the tongue, huh?
It's new.
CROW:
Very nice.
KENNY:
Gamera, here we are!
Hurry.
- Help me, Gamera!
- I want both of 'em,
skinless like a jerk chicken.
- You're in
good hands with Gamera.
- Eyes, teeth, nose, hair.
- It's fun!
- [indistinct]
JOEL:
Hey, he's flying the red eye.
Heh.
TOM SERVO:
Because it's...
- Gamera, down here, save us.
Isn't he great?
Gamera!
- Go team, go!
- [indistinct]
- I don't remember the words,
do you?
- No, not at all.
- La, la, la, la, la.
- We should have
a [indistinct] down.
- ♪ Gamera is really neat
Gamera is full of meat ♪
♪ We believe in Gamera ♪
KENNY:
Gamera!
- ♪ Take it to the
[indistinct] ♪
- ♪ Spam spam spam
Spam spam spam... ♪
- ♪ Gamera Gamera ♪
♪ Spam spam spam ♪
♪ Gamera is full of meat
Gamera is really neat ♪
♪ We believe in Gamera ♪
- [indistinct] ...wonderful.
I love Gamera.
- Love, that's all girls
think of.
JOEL:
We're talking about a lizard!
TOM SERVO:
Hm, hm.
Is that so wrong?
CROW:
Woo, hoo. Nice landing, buddy.
Uh, sorry
about the whiplash, kids.
Eh, eh.
- Thank you!
- Come on, Kenny.
We've no time to lose.
We better try
and get some help.
- Senorita Gamera.
I never understood that.
- What, no tip?
- Gamera, thank you.
I hope to see you very soon.
- Yeah, you're already acting
as if Gamera was all yours.
CROW:
This is sick, people,
really sick.
TOM SERVO:
[indistinct]
What a soulless experience.
JOEL:
He toasted our parents.
- Where are we?
No one's around.
- 'Cause nobody lives here.
- What are we going to do,
Kenny?
- We better go then,
no use staying here. Hurry!
CROW:
I could write a sonnet
about that, darn it!
TOM SERVO:
Slag heap babies... in color.
- Stay off the moors!
- Whooosh!
- Um?
TOM SERVO:
John the Baptist.
- Um, who are you?
What are you doing here?
- Just slouching
towards Bethlehem.
- When we left the spaceship,
we must have gone
into another time period.
- Can that happen?
- Yeah, time traveling
is what they call it,
and you can use it to travel
in the past or in the future...
CROW: How old is he?
- ...and end up in another time.
- What are you mumbling about?
- You seem to be
from another world.
TOM SERVO:
Here, have some
honey and locusts.
- I'm sorry.
We were on a spaceship
traveling through this galaxy
and then we found ourselves
right here.
- Please forgive us.
It's really
the spaceship's fault.
- Maybe he doesn't understand...
it's too technical.
- Oh, are you the ones
that were caught
by those evil people
who came down
from the planet Zigra?
- You already know,
who told you?
CROW:
I saw the first reel!
- There was
a special news bulletin
about you on the radio.
- It's just a radio.
KENNY:
Excuse me, sir,
would you please tell us
what year this is?
- It's the year 1985,
of course.
I think you two ought to
stop dreaming like that
and wake up.
Otherwise you might find
yourself in another time zone.
- Your clothes
don't look like the clothes
people wear in 1985,
why is that?
TOM SERVO:
Yeah, well,
you're wearing
a doll's dress, honey.
- You see.
The great warlord Yamamoto
came to settle on this island
over 800 years ago
with all his families
and possessions.
CROW:
You've been sniffing the glue,
haven't you, Gramps?
- I know where ancestor Noah
helped him to settle
on this island
and it's been called
Noah Island ever since,
and in honor
of that great occasion,
Lord Yamamoto
wore these clothes,
and so ever since then,
these clothes have been
worn by all the descendents
of the great Noah.
TOM SERVO:
No wonder they're stinky.
- Is this the island
near Kamagawa
where the Marine
Life Center is?
- Uh-hm.
- Oh, am I glad of that!
- You boys are stupid
'cause I knew that all along.
- Ha, ha, ha, ha.
- It's...
- Could I have a comment please
[indistinct] was attacked?
TOM SERVO:
Hi, thanks for comin'.
Go right in.
Yes, yep, yep, yep.
Yes, Spencer.
- Yes, yes,
I like all the festivals here.
- Yes, yes. Festival seating,
yes, people.
- Right this way, no shoving.
- Yes, yes.
- Now listen, children,
until your fathers
regain consciousness,
you're the only ones
who can tell us
about the Zigra space ship.
We'd like you to describe it
and answer a few questions...
do you think you can?
- Yes, I can do that.
- I can do that, too.
- For a price.
- What was the spaceship like?
- The same as the ones
we see on television.
- Television?
That's very strange.
- Don't you ever
look at television?
- I think you're old-fashioned.
- Now be polite.
[CHUCKLES]
- Brat!
- Now tell us about
the Zigra creatures.
KENNY:
They're just like us.
They have two hands and feet
and speak our language.
- Our language?
HELEN:
But we only saw one Zigra woman.
- Oh, the Zigran was a woman.
- Viva la Zigra!
- Yes, but, my Mama
is a whole lot prettier.
- Yes, mine is much prettier
than her, too.
CROW AND TOM SERVO:
I know!
- No, my Mama's prettier.
- No, mine is much prettier.
- Well, my mom can
beat up your mom.
- Okay, Okay.
The two of you are right.
Both of your Mamas
are very pretty.
TOM SERVO:
Well, what's that
supposed to mean?
- Did the Zigra woman
have any special ability?
KENNY:
Special ability, what's that?
- It's something that,
that ordinary people can't do...
a special skill.
- I understand now.
There are lots of very
unusual skills in our house.
Daddy always makes noises
while he's drinking,
and strange sounds
while he's eating.
TOM SERVO:
Uh, save that for the adult
children meeting, okay?
- Getting back
to the spaceship,
can you tell us more about it?
- No, nothing much, really.
They were very unfriendly
and not nice to us.
They didn't give us anything
to eat or anything to drink,
not even a Coke.
- What is it with her
and the Coke?
- Hmpf.
- [indistinct] back in.
- Shall we take a little break?
- Yes, please.
- We have to wait
until the two men
have recovered consciousness.
JOEL:
They're... garnishing
him with olives.
TOM SERVO:
Hm.
- Are you ready?
- Yes.
- Get the [indistinct].
- Pulse and blood pressure
are normal.
We'll check
the brain waves first.
- Right.
JOEL:
Visiting hours are over, folks.
TOM SERVO:
Let's see here.
Anaconda's down,
bonds are pretty bad,
but the Nikkei is holding up.
- I can't believe it!
- What is it, doctor?
TOM SERVO:
We have a machine
that goes "ping".
- Most unusual.
The brainwaves are not those
of a normal human being.
The activity
seems to be reduced.
- Oh, David Duke's brainwaves.
- It's hypnotism, doctor.
I saw her do it.
She snapped her fingers,
and then he fell asleep.
- Yes, it's hypnotism.
I saw her too.
- Hmpf.
- Doctor, these men have to be
awakened right away.
- I realize that.
I assure you, Commander,
we tried every means
at our disposal,
only with these two here,
it's not just
a simple case of hypnotism.
TOM SERVO:
It's a case of
Mommy doesn't love me blues.
- UN Headquarters
is calling you, Commander.
- Hm, doctor, it's important.
You must find a way
to wake these men.
- Yes.
CROW:
And find a handsome prince.
- Mama.
JOEL:
Don't let your babies
grow up to be cowboys.
KENNY [SOBBING]:
Oh, Papa, Papa, Papa.
CROW:
Oh, Mama.
TOM SERVO:
What is this,
Yentl all of a sudden?
JOEL:
I wish I could really act.
- Yes, Rona speaking.
I'm the Third Defense
Army Commander.
CROW:
Oh, the great Third Army
Commander.
- Very well, sir.
We'll take action right away.
JOEL:
[indistinct]
- Listen, UN Headquarters
has decided to attack
Zigra at once.
Prepare to leave immediately.
Get everything ready.
- Yes sir.
[♪♪♪]
- Well, you know,
spirits are kinda dim up here
on the Satellite of Love
after what amounts
to watching the same movie
like six times in your life,
so I came up with
a little art therapy
for the robots
so they could help me
feel a little bit better.
Okay, you guys,
hey, hey, hey, hey.
- Ooops, sorry.
- Do you remember
the assignment?
- Oh yeah.
- Okay, make a diorama
in a shoe box
based on one of
the Gamera moves,
and tell
a little bit about it.
Okay, who's first?
- Um.
- Um, um.
JOEL:
Tom?
Do you wanna go first?
Okay. Here's your box.
- Okay, mine, I chose
from Gamera versus Barugon.
- Okay.
TOM SERVO: Okay.
Be careful with...
JOEL:
Can you bring that in Cambot?
Come on.
TOM SERVO:
Be careful with that.
It's not dry yet.
JOEL:
Okay, do you want to
tell us about,
tell us about it?
TOM SERVO:
Okay, here we see
the mighty Barugon,
his huge hulking mass
towering over downtown Tokyo.
His terror-inducing face
locked forever
in a hideous death mask,
ooh, razor-sharp fangs
drip deadly venom
could cut the strongest hemp
rope like it was cotton floss.
There is no escape from
his battering ram tongue
as he slipped up
the denizens of Japan
like some horrific nightmare,
roaming cross
between an anteater
and the devil dog himself.
Chained forever and servant
to the Beastmaster
demonic farmer
of the underworld.
[indistinct]
Spoken like Beelzebub.
- Tom, Tom, Buddy, Buddy,
lighten up.
You're all done.
TOM SERVO:
Do you like the way
I used Lego for
[indistinct] venom?
JOEL:
Oh, yeah, that's good
and it looks like you also
renewed your subscription
to the Steven King
book club. Okay.
ROBOTS: How did he know?
- Okay, who's next?
- Oh, oh, oh, me, me,
oh, oh, oh.
- Okay.
Crow, we'll do you next.
Okay, here's yours.
CROW:
Okay. Um, all right, all right.
My favorite scene and the one
that I have rendered in
the exciting play-doh form
is the monster Gyaos.
ROBOTS:
Cool, ah.
CROW:
Gyaos is very big
and everyone runs away
with a flat head.
ROBOTS:
Um?
CROW:
Oh, with a flat head
that shoots laser beams,
shown here simulated
with pipe cleaners.
Gyaos terrorizes
the people of Japan.
Green gas shoots out
from his armpits
and they kill him
by keeping him out
until the sun came up
and he died.
TOM SERVO:
Hey, is it okay
that he used pipe cleaners?
CROW:
You used Lego.
TOM SERVO:
I used stupid pipe cleaners.
JOEL:
You guys.
Listen, you both kinda
went outside the perimeters
of the assignment,
but you know,
I think it turned out good.
You showed your own
individual creativity.
- See.
- Okay now, Gypsy's next.
- Cuckoo.
- Okay, you ready?
Okay, let's see.
Let's pull yours up. Okay.
Bring it in, Cambot.
- Oh.
GYPSY:
Okay, Richard Basehart
of the [indistinct]
and David Hedison
with the guy who played
the chief.
JOEL:
Oh, that's great.
You did a really good job.
That's nice. Okay.
Well, I wanna show you
my favorite scene
of the whole series of Gamera.
GYPSY:
Surprise, it's a [indistinct].
JOEL: No...
ROBOTS: What is it? What is it?
Is it a puppy?
JOEL:
No, it's not a puppy...
it's...
It's all of us together,
a family.
ROBOTS:
Oh no, we got movie's up!
TOM SERVO:
What fun.
- [indistinct] moment.
- Hello, is this the party
to whom I'm speaking?
- Excuse me, sir.
It seems the whole squadron
has been wiped out.
- Neat!
- Is there any way
to stop Zigra?
- He must have a weakness.
- [indistinct]
Drop more depth charges.
TOM SERVO:
That would [indistinct] of them.
- We must first think
of the people's safety.
- Sergeant,
order all of the people
to be evacuated at once.
JOEL:
All at once?
TOM SERVO:
Eew.
CROW:
Hey, I think I see
Charlton Heston.
TOM SERVO:
You did it,
you finally did it!
CROW:
Good.
- [indistinct]
CROW: Wow. Cool.
ZIGRA:
You must find
those two children.
TOM SERVO:
[indistinct]
about that.
ZIGRA:
I want you to catch them
and kill them immediately.
- Yes, Zigra.
JOEL:
Do I get a per diem
when I'm on Earth?
- Oops!
- Wait, I can't run so fast.
We have no time to lose.
We must hurry.
We were given orders
to evacuate at once.
I can't walk so fast.
TOM SERVO:
[indistinct] Kids evacuated.
CROW:
Oh, ooo.
- Where are we going?
Oh, ah!
TOM SERVO:
Hey, did you get that
at Betsy Johnson's?
- Uh, ugh.
CROW: I love doin' that.
CROW:
Sex appeal.
TOM SERVO:
Um, hah, hah, ha.
CROW:
The Maidenform woman,
you never know
where she'll show up.
TOM SERVO:
I had this dream once.
JOEL:
I thought I'd blend in
with this costume.
CROW and TOM SERVO:
Ha, ha.
- Not very good.
That's not much
of a catch today.
- Yes, they're all scared
of the monsters
and no one went out to fish.
That's all we got.
- I'll buy them all.
- Just a minute.
Whoa, whoa.
- They were reserved for me.
TOM SERVO:
Jimmy Shirtround.
- Listen here, you.
You may think running
a hotel makes you a big shot.
Only I don't think so,
and I tell you all that fish
was reserved for me,
so you can just go jump
in a lake for all I care.
TOM SERVO:
Again with a finger?
- Oh, really?
You want the fish
to feed your dolphins
whereas I need fish
to feed people.
There's a great difference.
- Oh yeah?
- Everyone is to evacuate
immediately.
- I just did!
- Wha-,
who's going to buy the fish?
- Me!
- All right. You two decide
and pay me later!
JOEL:
Hey, Estelle Getty
wants her hat back.
- You better get going.
- You crazy?
The animals at Sea World
are hungry
and they're waiting for me
to come and feed them,
so I'm taking that fish.
If you know
what's good for you,
you better get going yourself.
- Hm.
- No joking!
I have to feed our guest
and I need that fish.
- What, you're guests
evacuated hours ago.
You said so yourself,
hours ago!
- It's, it's true,
and most of the other hotels
are empty, only...
TOM SERVO [YELLING]:
What does this have
to do with anything?
CROW:
I was about to ask
the same question.
- Running a hotel
is just like running a ship,
and you don't desert it.
- Oh, what a bi-r-r-d.
- Ha! What's the point of
staying in the hotel
if all your guests
have gone away?
CROW:
I get the Volcano Room
to myself.
- Come and see!
- All right,
I'll come and see,
only you'll be sorry
if this is some kind of trick.
TOM SERVO:
Hey, the Hot L Tokyo. Ha.
CROW:
And now the brilliant
fish-buying sequence
shall continue.
- You see that soldier there.
It's because I didn't run away
that those soldiers are here.
Our hotel was invaded
by all sorts of soldiers
and dozens of reporters,
and as long as
one person remains,
it's my duty
to stay on right here,
and that's why
I've got to have the fish.
Got it, brother?
- Nothing doing.
CROW:
Everyone will be seated
during the famous
fish arguments.
- All I care about are
my seals and my dolphins.
Nothing else,
so I'm keeping the fish.
You got it, brother?
- Will Wayne Newton
keep the fish?
Stay tuned.
- I'm a very stubborn man,
but he's even more so.
TOM SERVO:
Hm, hm.
- Big shot,
just who does he think he is.
A hotel manager indeed.
I showed him. Huh?
CROW:
Joel, why do you suppose
they had the sudden
catering subplot?
JOEL:
Uh, the Japanese
love the food industry.
They often use it...
- Where you going?
- Who cares?
- Everyone was told to evacuate.
- Are you from Sea World?
ZIGRA WOMAN:
Yeah.
I have to go there.
I want to get to
the Marine Life Center.
I have to see
two little children.
- Children,
you mean, Kenny and Helen?
- That's right.
- What a coincidence!
TOM SERVO:
Fish argument theater
will be back,
but first a scene from plot
convenience playhouse.
- I don't believe I've seen
you around here before...
- At least not this view!
- I came yesterday.
- Are you an actress?
TOM SERVO:
Yes, but I really
want to direct.
- Pilot.
- Whoa, hmpf.
JOEL:
Stay on the road....
is there a closer spot?
- Here we are.
The children live
in this building.
You can't miss them.
- Thanks,
you're a real gentleman.
CROW:
Would you like to grab a bo,
a bite to eat sometime?
I've got lots of fish.
[PANTING]
Nibble.
TOM SERVO:
About face, attention!
Eyes, woo, hoo, hoo.
JOEL:
Clothes, that's what I need.
Clothes.
TOM SERVO:
Ah, you're dressed sensibly.
JOEL:
Oh that's what she's using
her winky blinky for.
- Everyone
is to evacuate immediately.
I repeat.
Everyone is
to evacuate immediately.
CROW [BREATHLESS]:
Two more laps, ha, ha.
TOM SERVO:
Say, sister, that dress
is headed for trouble
and it's taking you with it.
- Everyone
is to evacuate immediately.
I repeat.
Everyone is
to evacuate immediately.
CROW:
She's got ultra-bright eyes,
ooh.
Works every time.
I get more clothes this way.
Like GI Joe.
TOM SERVO:
I've always admired people
who could sleep anywhere.
I wish I could.
CROW:
Yeah, I know what you mean.
- We have received reports
from all parts of the world.
No fighter bombers,
battleships,
or missiles are left.
Most areas are
completely defenseless.
Food and water
are in short supply.
It's a very critical situation.
Our weapons
are no match for Zigra.
- Has the UN considered
using the H-bomb?
TOM SERVO:
Shut up, Dad.
CROW: Sit down!
- Of course they did,
but they reached the conclusion
it was too dangerous.
It could kill
our own people too.
- That's incredible!
You mean, we have no strategy
in case of attack?
- Sorry, we're doing
all we can.
This enemy seems
almost invincible.
CROW:
I'm good, I'm really good! Huh?
Come on, wake up!
CROW:
Boy, that's fun.
- What's the matter?
TOM SERVO:
Somebody get me a gun.
I'm gonna shoot this coward.
- Commander,
he seems to be in a trance.
He walks if someone
leads him around,
only he shows
no reactions whatsoever.
JOEL:
We'd cure him,
but we need the eggs!
- Hm, hm, same symptoms
as the other two men.
Take him over
to the clinic.
- Right.
- Commander...
TOM SERVO:
I saw what you did there, man.
It was really wild.
I was there.
I saw all was cool, dude.
Hey. Attica, I mean that, man.
- No, absolutely not!
- We bring you news
of the latest developments
in the present crisis.
An earthquake of magnitude 13
has just turned the city
into a sea of flames.
Even the radio tower
is a tangle of molten iron.
CROW:
I'm bored.
Switch it over to Care Bears.
- Ah, Gamera!
- Oh, it's Gamera!
Gamera has come!
TOM SERVO:
Hey, where's the CNN graphics?
You know,
we're in Zigra crisis.
- He'll save us!
CROW: Ha, ha.
- We regret we must
end this broadcast.
The flames are growing nearer.
TOM SERVO:
And liquid metal.
- It's become
too dangerous here.
Zigra has destroyed
thousands of homes
and killed many families.
ROBOTS and JOEL:
Doo, doo, doo, dooo-tle,
do, do, do.
Doo, doo, doo, doooo-tle,
- No, we're not going to
give in to that monster.
- Oh no!
JOEL:
Look, she can take over
the world,
but she can't sneak
upon these pesky kids!
TOM SERVO:
Oh, yeah, and look,
travel through
the fourth dimension,
no problem, but stuffed animals,
look out!
- Come back,
come back here!
Ugh.
CROW:
Great music, huh?
JOEL:
Sounds like it's from
any Don Knotts film.
CROW:
Yep.
- I won't hurt you.
JOEL:
What?
[RASPBERRY SOUND]
CROW:
Hey, love that.
ZIGRA WOMAN:
Wait, I won't hurt you.
- This way!
TOM SERVO:
Just enough time to go in
and hit the confessional...
huh.
Father forgive me
for I have, uh...
CROW:
Thank you.
Uh, no waiting
on telescope four.
Go ahead, four.
CROW:
Mew, mew, mew.
You know actually I think
this is the soundtrack
from Chevy Van.
TOM SERVO:
Hey, did I just get faced?
CROW:
Uh-hm.
I see London,
I see France...
JOEL:
Oh, I do, too.
TOM SERVO:
I see... heavens.
CHILDREN:
She's right behind us.
- Come here,
I just want to talk to you.
CROW:
Please clean our tank!
ROBOTS:
What?
TOM SERVO:
That's Tom Arnold's old
[indistinct].
CROW:
Okay, sorry.
Doom, doom, doom.
JOEL:
A lot of seating there.
CROW:
Well, they do get
an overflowing crowd
at that tuna tank, you know.
- I won't hurt you!
Wait for me.
Don't [indistinct].
TOM SERVO:
Hey, hey, look.
Buddy Hackett's token up.
- Do you know that girl?
- Of course you know her.
That's Lora Lee Barrett. Hmm.
CROW:
But everyone knew her as Nancy.
Heh, heh, heh.
- Lora Lee! Lora Lee!
Wait!
CROW:
Lora Lee, let's live together.
- May I have your attention,
please?
JOEL:
You know, these Clare Prophet
seminars are all alike.
CROW:
Yeah, that's for sure...
Wild.
Wild rebels.
Nutty, girlie rebels.
Hey, if she comes up here
we can see up her skirt again.
TOM SERVO:
Say, Crow.
CROW:
Sorry.
JOEL:
Please, don't make...huh?
- Okay let's switch.
TOM SERVO:
Hey, you kids.
We're not air-conditioning
the outside,
in or out, come on!
JOEL:
[indistinct]... and drums.
CHILDREN:
Yay, hah.
CROW:
We rule!
JOEL:
Oop, now she's going
to Knott's Berry Farm.
CROW:
[indistinct]
TOM SERVO:
Elaine, Elaine, Elai--
Rats! Now what?
Thank goodness for new Secret.
JOEL:
Candy pants.
[PANTING]
- I'm exhausted.
My legs won't go any further.
CROW:
That's a crisp Kodacolor world
they live in, isn't it.
- Gamera, I wish
he would get here soon.
CROW:
Uh-hm.
- He's the only one
strong enough to beat her.
Gamera can lick anyone.
- Where is he?
JOEL:
I want a Coke!
- Gamera!
- Help us, Gamera!
TOM SERVO:
Okay, Okay, you've been
riding me the whole film.
Did they ever invite me
over for dinner? No.
When they're in trouble
it's Gamera this and Gamera...
CROW:
I think the brain of a clown
runs this ship.
JOEL:
Hmpf.
Looks like something a Shriner
would wear when he's drunk.
CROW:
What do you mean, all the time?
JOEL:
Oo-o-
TOM SERVO:
Now, let's see.
Two blocks past Davy Jones'
Locker, take a right.
[MONSTER ROARS]
CROW:
Ah, looks like an electric bowl
of Trix cereal.
It's tediously delicious.
[indistinct] minutes.
JOEL:
It's hard to get
a sense of scale here.
Is that really big
or really small?
CROW:
I, I can't tell.
TOM SERVO:
So Okay, listen to this one.
I says to the man, I says,
all right, now this is great...
CROW:
No, Gamera.
JOEL:
That is the grandest hat of all,
hands down.
CROW:
Absolutely!
TOM SERVO:
Hm.
Huh?
CROW:
Heh, heh, heh, heh.
Enjoy! Heh, heh.
JOEL:
Oh, that's great.
Gamera's gonna play
stadium checkers.
CROW:
Huh?
TOM SERVO:
He's got a hat mat at him.
CROW:
Yep.
TOM SERVO:
Nah, nah, nah, nah, nah.
Can't catch me,
stupid old hat.
Tee, hee, hee.
[MONSTER ROARS]
CROW:
Raspberry red.
JOEL:
Hey, nobody said
we were playing tackle.
That's not fair.
[MONSTER ROARS]
CROW:
Ugh, huh, ugh.
Eeew!
I hate you, I hate you,
Mr. Bowl Candy Dish.
Eeew!
TOM SERVO:
Oh, just checking
the hull structure here.
CROW:
Oooh.
JOEL:
Hm. That's pretty neat.
He can hire out
as a waffle iron.
CROW:
Why would you need to
iron your waffles?
[MONSTER ROARS]
TOM SERVO:
Missed me, missed me.
Now you gotta kiss me.
[RASPBERRY SOUND]
CROW:
Nah, ugh.
Ugh.
Hm.
Synthesis, I presume.
TOM SERVO:
Hm, squirting a little
KC Masterpiece on there.
Hm.
Egad.
Yep, Hell.
Hell is for children.
JOEL:
Wow,
how does he do that underwater.
Is he packing acetylene?
CROW:
Aw, suspension of disbelief
or not.
Ha, I don't get it.
JOEL:
You know, uh,
these films are weird.
TOM SERVO:
Yep, yeah, yep.
CROW:
Don't get it at all.
TOM SERVO:
Terrific. He's fighting.
He's fighting Captain Emo.
Huh, I mean Captain Nemo.
CROW:
Ah, or Leonard Nimoy.
TOM SERVO:
I was just thinking,
I'd be a fish.
CROW:
Yeah, look.
Zigra fit the battle
to Gamera, Gamera, Gamera.
Zigra fit
the battle of Gamera.
JOEL:
He's gonna turn into butter
pretty soon.
TOM SERVO:
Uh-huh.
CROW:
He says, hey, scratch my neck.
Come on.
Coochy, coo.
JOEL:
You know they grow so fast
when they get to that age.
TOM SERVO:
Gamera looks like a coelacanth,
don't you think?
CROW:
Hm.
TOM SERVO:
Hey, hey,
even I don't believe that.
Come on,
back up a few frames...
and so what, he's bigger.
He's still stupid.
CROW:
He'd make a great can opener.
Look at that beak.
TOM SERVO:
You look at it, I'm better.
JOEL:
Well, he's got a cat's eye
and a bird's beak.
Hm.
[MONSTER ROARS]
TOM SERVO:
How often can you use
this shot of me?
Cut away! There!
[MONSTER ROARS]
TOM SERVO:
Hey, can you lend me a fin?
Ha, ha, ha.
How about a couple of clams?
Ha, ha.
He, he.
I just said that
for the hell of it.
[MONSTER ROARS]
JOEL:
I want you to get these
pool toys
out of the living room.
CROW:
Ooh, oh, don't bite him.
It'll make your fillings buzz.
TOM SERVO:
Uh, forget connection
to these men.
This is a wall hanger
for sure here.
- Oh, no.
I left my windows open!
JOEL:
Hey, it's Handel's
Out of Water music,
what do you know?
CROW:
Look, Gamera's got a jet ski.
He's skiing go-go.
TOM SERVO:
Oh, yeah.
Gamera baby.
[♪♪♪]
- Everybody must evacuate
at once.
JOEL: Oooh, again?
- This is a final warning!
CROW:
Wow.
- Don't you worry.
No matter what,
whatever happens...
CROW:
He's [indistinct] Jack.
- ...I'll never leave ya.
You can count on that.
Not in a million years.
JOEL:
What a kook!
CHILDREN:
Help, help us.
JOEL:
The fish are screaming.
CROW:
No, no, no. It's all right.
ZIGRA WOMAN:
Wait for me. Stop running!
I won't hurt you.
TOM SERVO:
That's the Lucille Ball
of Japan.
CROW:
Ricky-y-y. Ah, ah, ah.
- You heard that announcement.
I believe we ought to
transport them
to a safe place right away.
JOEL:
There's a hospital at Sea World?
CROW:
Well, I guess so.
- Careful, careful.
TOM SERVO:
Snap!
CROW:
Uh, no Michael,
we don't need any more
dead fish in the emergency room.
But they're sturgeons.
- Oh, Kathryn.
- Yes.
- I see you're having a,
a guide evacuate
the two children.
CROW: A guide?
- They'd run away
and they're not easy to catch.
- No.
I, I didn't ask any guide
to look after the children,
so I...
JOEL:
They can evacuate themselves now
that they're old enough.
- Well, that's funny.
- Uh, doctor?
Have they regained
consciousness?
- No, unfortunately
- That's very strange.
They don't look like
they can see anything,
but they can walk around
without bumping
into anything.
TOM SERVO:
Just like Grampa.
- Ah, do you think maybe the...
- The what?
CROW:
I think you should
call Oliver Sacks.
- Uh, come with me.
- Sergeant, go with them.
- Right.
CROW:
What a loon!
- Excuse me, would you
like the dolphin now, sir?
JOEL:
He's talking to the TV.
- Ah, I'm not a scientist,
but I do understand
technical things...
But this dolphin is blind,
yet it never seems
to bump into a wall.
Oh, I always thought
it was very strange.
Is it possible that dolphins
have some kind of instinct to,
a sort of sixth sense?
- If I may...
- The dolphin is endowed
with a very special faculty.
It sends out a supersonic
signal that is continually
bouncing between itself
and an object.
CROW:
Yeah, we like to call it sonar.
- ...avoids the wall.
CROW:
Next on Discover...
- Same as the sonar device
they have on submarines?
- Yes. That's right.
CROW: Dr. Dull is back.
- [indistinct] waves
for a long period causes
sudden physiological conditions.
It could affect
the human brain.
TOM SERVO:
The Schuman brain?
- Then maybe that's
what happened to these two.
Could their brains be working
like those dolphins' brains?
CROW:
Could they be guided
by ancient astronauts?
- Yes.
Zigra is a creature
from an aquatic world,
so it sent out
a supersonic signal
in order to control willpower...
JOEL:
Oh, everything's supersonic
with you.
CROW:
I don't know.
- I know a method
that will cure it.
Here, here.
Lend me your transceiver.
TOM SERVO:
Lend me a tenor.
- Ahhh...
TOM SERVO:
No, I said a tenor.
- Ahhh...
[GROANS]
TOM SERVO:
A little higher.
- Ahhh...
CROW:
Okay, it works.
So they don't like Yoko Ono,
so what's the point?
- Aha-a-a-a...
JOEL:
Daddy, you're embarrassing me.
[GROANS]
CROW:
Duh!
- Henry!
- Papa!
You're conscious.
TOM SERVO:
And yet you're still drooling!
- Why are we here?
- What happened to me?
- Don't worry, Papa.
Are you all right?
CROW:
Well, sure.
Now how much money
did we raise?
You know the kids...
- The transceiver wave
has made them normal again,
and we owe the idea
to our good dolphin trainer.
- Ha, ha, ha.
Don't forget we owe it
to the dolphins, too.
Heh, heh, heh.
JOEL and ROBOTS:
Oh, ah.
- All the reporters have been
hypnotized now as well.
CROW:
Mt. Rushmore.
- No.
- Zigra!
It's that Zigra creature.
- What?
- Ugh, no, put me down.
CROW:
For this afternoon's show,
we'll drown two schoolchildren.
- If you come closer,
I'll feed them to the dolphins.
Now you come on.
TOM SERVO:
Hey, I got dibs
on the [indistinct]...
on my mother's side.
JOEL:
Hey, you know, her plan
wasn't really that good.
CROW:
No.
- Then they'll die.
- You let those kids go!
You let those kids go!
ZIGRA WOMAN:
You're coming with me, you hear?
- Ahhh...Ahhh...
JOEL and ROBOTS:
Higher.
- Ahhh.
JOEL: Porn on the radio,
I don't think it's gonna work.
KENNY:
Come on, Helen, let's run!
ZIGRA WOMAN:
Ugh!
TOM SERVO:
Hey, twirl a perp!
CROW:
She's dancing go-go.
CHILDREN:
Mama!
CROW:
Oooh, sis takes one in the face.
JOEL:
Quickly,
everybody stand around her.
JOEL and ROBOTS:
Ahhh...ahhh...ahhh.
Stay away from those
powerful hind legs, boys.
ZIGRA WOMAN:
Why am I here?
How did I get here?
TOM SERVO:
My God! What have I done?
ZIGRA WOMAN:
How did I get here?
I was just on the moon.
CROW:
Oh, you're going
to the moon, Alice.
- On the moon?
- Yes.
My name is Lora Lee Worth...
JOEL:
From "Gentlemen Prefer Blondes"?
ZIGRA WOMAN:
I was working at a moon base.
[RASPBERRY SOUND]
ZIGRA WOMAN:
I was riding on a moon jeep...
TOM SERVO:
I was eating a Moon Pie...
I had just mooned
a passing moon jeep...
ZIGRA WOMAN:
...and suddenly
there was a mysterious ray,
and I got very dizzy
and I couldn't move.
Then I lost consciousness.
JOEL:
And then I was
color-separated.
TOM SERVO:
Ooh.
- And then I woke up here
but I don't remember
anything else.
CROW:
You're just like Patty Hearst,
aren't you dear?
- I understand now.
The ray made you
that monster's captive.
You lost your willpower,
and Zigra forced you
to carry out his evil schemes.
TOM SERVO:
Oh, and uh,
you're married to me.
Yeah, yeah, that
was the other thing.
- Is there anything
you could tell us
about Zigra's weaknesses?
Where is he vulnerable?
CROW:
Well, he likes to
bet on the dogs.
- I don't remember
anything at all...
where I was or what I did.
- Is there no way
he could be defeated?
- We can't
just let him conquer us.
- There are limits
to what we humans can do.
TOM SERVO:
Oh, come on.
Everyone pick up the radios
and say, "Ahhh".
KENNY:
I know what to do.
I think we should ask
Gamera to save us.
Gamera is clever.
He can do things
that no one else can.
JOEL:
Another preschooler saves Japan.
KENNY:
He can defeat Zigra.
CROW:
Kenny, you're brilliant.
Take a kiss out of petty cash.
- You see, Gamera is powerless.
He's lying upside-down
in the sea now.
HELEN:
He's in the sea,
but he's not dead, is he?
TOM SERVO:
Oops, zing.
She zoomed me.
What do you know?
- Commander, I know
that it sounds unlikely,
but Gamera
may still be alive down there.
- Yes,
I think we should find out.
Gamera is our only hope
to save the Earth
from destruction.
- Is there any way to see
if Gamera is still alive?
JOEL:
Yeah, just leave a message
on his machine.
- We're very well equipped here.
We've even got the latest
diving bathyscaphe, Commander.
- Give us your authorization
and we'll go look for Gamera.
CROW:
We might even look for Emilio
while we're down there.
- Very well. Get going.
- Our Papas are really clever,
aren't they?
- Yeah, tee, hee.
TOM SERVO: Your puppets?
JOEL:
Now wait a minute.
Here come
the flying Crest tubes.
- Crest! Crest!
CROW:
You know, if you look
at that rock [indistinct],
it looks like Gamera's foot.
JOEL:
Slit rock.
CROW:
Oh, I bet it is Gamera's foot.
JOEL:
That terrapin is stationary.
TOM SERVO:
Oooh!
You know, TV repair
is really my game,
but thanks for bringing me
down with you.
CROW: Oh, look at that, they got
a bass finder on the dash.
TOM SERVO:
Fass Binder, I love his films.
CROW and JOEL:
Bass finder!
TOM SERVO:
Oh.
- Bathyscope.
Come in, chopper.
- Chopper here, over.
- Come in a little closer,
about 30 feet.
- Roger.
JOEL: Hm.
Getting the picture.
Yeah, that's Gamera all right.
TOM SERVO: Well, and he's got a
nasty case of gingivitis.
JOEL:
Okay, now cough.
CROW:
Remember the bowl cut?
- Gamera seems to be dead.
- We'll try the sonar to see
if his brain waves
are functioning.
JOEL: Ah.
- Roger.
- Tom, turn on the sonar.
TOM SERVO:
Well, the sonar the better.
[indistinct]
CROW:
No, no, that's the machine
that goes "ping".
Turn on the sonar.
- I'm quite sure
Gamera was hit by a ray,
and it was the same sort of ray
that was used on me...
TOM SERVO:
Gamma ray? Aldo Ray?
- Yes, I think she's right.
- Hm.
JOEL:
It's okay to like
the hot chick again.
She's on our side.
CROW:
Bottom of the seventh, two out.
Ryan blows it past Conseco.
You know, True Value
hardware stores are...
JOEL:
Microwave fish sticks are done.
Uh, what?
Oh, it's those meddling kids!
CROW:
No!
TOM SERVO:
Hey, you kids
aren't young enough
to be in here.
- Daddy, what is that sound?
- I can't stand it.
- What are you doing here?
- How did you brats
get in here? Huh?
- I'm sorry, Commander.
The two kids sneaked onboard
the bathyscaphe.
- Oh!
JOEL: Whoa, look.
He's [indistinct]
our daughters.
...we'll take them
along with us.
We've no other choice.
- Tha-a-a-a.
TOM SERVO:
He's a real scientist, that one.
- Tha-a-a-a.
TOM SERVO:
How sweet and charming.
- Mom, Helen's down there.
- Now get off there, come on.
CROW:
You want to
wipe the lens off now?
- Stay there.
- Would he be [indistinct]?
JOEL:
Get some Visine
and get the red out.
- What's this here, Daddy?
- Stop bothering us, Kenny.
Come on.
Don't be a nuisance.
- Helen.
TOM SERVO:
Hi, I'm your Time-Life operator.
- Not much progress.
Gamera has not responded yet.
We're going to intensify
the sound. Huh?
JOEL [WHISPERING]:
Let's let the water in.
[CHUCKLES]
At least the dad's
wearing a turtle neck.
That's good.
- Papa!
- Zigra's there!
- Huh?
TOM SERVO:
[indistinct]
CROW:
They all die
in a yellow Bathysphere.
[CHUCKLES]
TOM SERVO:
Uh, Tranquility Base here.
The Eagle has landed.
- Come in, Bathyscope.
Come in, Bathyscope.
JOEL:
All [indistinct]
went on in the Bathyscope.
- Tom, here.
- Okay.
- Fine, uh, fine.
Everything's fine.
TOM SERVO:
Except for that part that isn't.
- We've been hit.
The Bathyscope's leaking.
We're gonna have to ditch her
and don't worry.
We'll be all right.
TOM SERVO:
From the bottom of the ocean...
- Turn it on.
- Okay.
JOEL and ROBOTS:
It's a party. Whoa!
- Hey, it's a good thing
I converted Tom Servo
into this pony keg.
Now we're gonna have enough
delicious Dad's root beer
for the game tomorrow.
- Yeah.
- And you know it.
TOM SERVO:
Oh, oh, say, that reminds me,
uh, Tom, you're supposed
to have your picks in
before the game starts.
You can't turn them in
Monday morning
and try to say you won
14 and 1 on Sunday.
- Oh, well, yeah,
look who's talking.
I mean, I can't believe
you picked the Vikings again!
They almost never win
on natural grass.
Now the Packers back in '68,
now there was a team.
- Yeah, yeah,
but for Vince Lombardi
and the Green Bay Packers,
there would be another day.
- Oh, hey.
- Well, come on.
- No. [indistinct] was a Saint.
- Can I pour you one, Buddy?
- Yeah, sure, pour me one.
Hey, tilt that back.
Hey, hey, hey.
Come on. Where'd you
learn how to pour?
- You know what they say,
guys...
you don't buy root beer,
you rent it!
JOEL and ROBOTS:
Whoa! Oh!
- Quick, gimme rocket #9
[indistinct].
Wow, it's Kenny and Helen
from the moon.
It looks like they're riding
on the back of Gamera.
What a rush.
Man, this is a party!
Hey, how are you two doing?
- We're feeling really good.
- Well, we're feeling
really good, too, Kenny.
This is quite a surprise.
You know, the one thing
I've always wanted to ask you...
how come you little kids
are always the ones
with all the answers, hm?
- Gamera is good.
Gamera is friend of children.
- What?
- We filled up on fish.
CROW:
Well yeah, but what if...
- It's fun.
- I'm feeling really good.
CROW:
Well, Joel,
this is embarrassing.
Are these more
child actors gone bad?
TOM SERVO:
Yeah, what's the problem
you two?
Aren't you both
around 30 by now?
Aren't you a little old
to be hanging around Gamera?
- Gamera is my boyfriend...
TOM SERVO:
Uh-hm.
- Daddy, I want a Coke.
- Gamera's dancing go-go.
Eeew!
TOM SERVO:
- Well, geez, we better...
get back to our party
or something,
uh, unless anybody's got
something they want to say.
- No, no.
- We love you, corn dog.
- I'm feeling really good!
- Uh, corn dog,
that must be you, Joel.
- And speaking of corn...
- Back after this.
[♪♪♪]
TOM SERVO:
Uh, oh. That was weird.
CROW:
They learned that move
on Star Trek.
- I'll fix this.
JOEL:
The British team has the ball.
TOM SERVO:
Right there.
CROW:
I'm hungry for a little
Japanese.
Heh, heh, heh.
KENNY:
Eck, that's Zigra!
JOEL:
Well, it's starting to lose
some of its credibility.
CROW:
I was thinking that
as a matter of fact.
- Don't be afraid.
We'll be all right.
Tom, how's the depth gauge?
Is it working?
- Ready pretty soon,
any second.
- Now you hold on
and be quiet.
TOM SERVO:
Okay, kids.
You know the drill.
Into this tube.
- 8.000.
CROW:
Bottles of sake in the wall.
- 9.000
CROW:
Bottles of sake in the wall.
- 10.000
CROW:
Bottles of sake in the wall.
- We're right on the bottom
of the ocean.
CROW:
The bottom of the ocean.
CHILDREN:
[indistinct] anymore!
JOEL:
Sorry, kids.
No [indistinct] here.
- Here, hold onto me.
TOM SERVO:
Hey, ow, you bit me!
CROW:
Ooops!
JOEL:
Dr. Henry, Mr. Wallace.
CROW:
Dr. Howard,
Dr. Fine, Dr. Howard.
- I'm in.
- You see us?
- Yes, we see you fine.
- Bathyscope here.
JOEL:
Does this bug you?
- Bathyscope, come in please.
- We here you.
Come in.
- Bathyscope here.
Can you hear us?
- Yes, we hear you.
- Can you hear us?
- Commander?
JOEL:
What is this,
Abbott and Costello? Yes!
- We can hear you fine.
- Are you all right?
- We're all right.
TOM SERVO:
Not feeling too good myself.
- Everyone's okay, considering.
And the Bathyscope
is still holding on.
Our depth is 1.200.
We're really worried
about the water pressure.
- How's the surfacing apparatus?
TOM SERVO:
Oh fine, and you?
- Not working yet.
We're checking it out.
That was a really bad tumble.
KENNY:
Daddy, what do we do
if we can't get up?
CROW:
Come on, you're the preschooler.
You're supposed
to know everything.
- How much oxygen is left?
JOEL:
Um, none.
- Enough for one hour.
[GASPS]
- [indistinct]
she's leaking pretty badly now.
TOM SERVO:
So am I.
I need a stronger waistband.
- You've got to go
and save them.
CROW:
Hey, I'm a general, let go.
HELEN:
Margie, Margie, Margie help me.
KENNY:
Save us!
JOEL:
Hey, you kids,
shut up back there.
Don't make me come back.
- Now don't worry.
We'll get out of here.
- Helen, Papa.
- Don't worry, Margie.
- Do you think
they can be saved in an hour?
TOM SERVO:
Why don't you ask
one of the kids.
They seem to know everything.
- Our latest nuclear submarine
could make a dive
of over 12.000 meters.
You know, I think
that there's a Bathyscope
along the French coast.
Only, I'm not sure it can be
brought here in an hour.
JOEL:
Okay, let's go there.
It'd be a nice vacation.
- Oh, no.
Are you just going to stay here
and let them all die?
CROW:
Yup, pretty much.
TOM SERVO:
Yup.
- Don't worry.
It's okay.
We'll fix
the surfacing apparatus.
We're not losing hope,
and don't you either.
- You'll make it!
TOM SERVO:
He's dead.
He's toast.
You'll be fine, Bob.
They're never
gonna get outta there.
CROW:
Our father in the bathysphere.
TOM SERVO:
Okay, who forgot to jiggle
the handle?
CROW:
Him.
- Okay.
JOEL:
You can get HBO now.
I think Beastmaster's on.
TOM SERVO:
All right.
CROW:
Yeah!
Um, think
they should be doing this
while standing in water?
JOEL:
Well the jets are working.
TOM SERVO:
Jets?
- Oh!
TOM SERVO:
Be sure to turn down the VCR
and the microwave
at the same time.
CROW:
What did I tell ya?
- Commander,
the surfacing apparatus
has been severely damaged.
- What's the matter?
What happened?
[indistinct], pease answer.
What's the matter?
TOM SERVO: This really bites.
- Uh, Zigra!
- A light! A light!
JOEL:
A kingdom for a light.
A light.
- Okay.
- Zigra's blinded by the light.
CROW:
Cut loose like a deuce,
another runner in the night.
- Yes!
JOEL:
It's light!
- Listen.
We just discovered
Zigra's weakness.
Zigra's a creature
that lives under the water,
a deep-sea monster.
TOM SERVO:
So?
- Gamera knew that
Zigra is afraid of the light...
so Gamera
pulled it up into the light.
He found its weaknesses
instinctively.
TOM SERVO:
You can't teach instincts
like that.
ZIGRA:
You people on Earth,
listen to me...
JOEL:
I want a cracker, a big one.
ZIGRA:
Surrender to me at once.
It's very easy for me
to destroy the Bathyscope.
CROW:
Must not be built Ford tough.
ZIGRA:
If you surrender
within an hour,
I promise you
I will save you.
TOM SERVO:
It would be like
surrendering to Kukla.
JOEL: Yeah.
CROW: In his palace.
ZIGRA:
If you do not surrender,
I will destroy the Bathyscope
and your friends
inside will die.
CROW:
Well, that kinda follows,
doesn't it?
ZIGRA:
This is my last warning.
I am losing my patience.
Zigra is your master now.
JOEL:
Hey, you're a fish.
ZIGRA:
And you will obey me
from now on.
CROW:
They're watching TNT,
one of our favorite networks.
- Zigra is a deep-sea monster,
and he loves to feed
on human beings.
JOEL:
Yeah, we figured that out,
thanks.
- And after
we surrender to Zigra,
he'll imprison us
in cages like animals
and keep us all
for his food.
- How's your supply of oxygen?
- Enough for about 60 minutes.
- Oh Papa!
TOM SERVO: Wait, wait.
I found some more oxygen
in a drawer, we're Okay.
- We'll surrender
to Zigra at once.
- Oh [indistinct] no.
JOEL:
Wait a minute!
CROW:
There's more...
- Bathyscope, you hear me.
We're not
going to let you die.
Sergeant,
call UN Headquarters.
- Right.
TOM SERVO:
This is a pickle, George.
This is a pickle.
- Zigra, do you hear me?
I admit,
you're more powerful
and advanced in science
than we are.
CROW:
Go on, I'm listening.
- We cannot defeat you.
Our weapons are too weak.
CROW:
Now tell me I'm pretty...
- We want only one thing...
the Bathyscope to be saved.
We surrender to you at once.
JOEL and ROBOTS:
Say please.
- Very well.
Turn off the light
in the Bathyscope.
CROW:
And give someone else
a turn in there.
JOEL:
You know, he's got
Lillian Hellman eyes.
CROW:
He does.
- We're saved now.
TOM SERVO:
Have you been saved?
- Is that right, Papa?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
TOM SERVO:
Uh, oh.
ZIGRA WOMAN:
You know even if you surrender,
mankind will become its food.
You mustn't trust Zigra.
Dr. Henry, listen.
You are an authority
on marine life, the greatest...
CROW:
Well, I do my best, over.
- ...Zigra's main
characteristic.
If you remember that,
you'll have a great weapon.
It's your only chance
to escape Zigra.
It's your only chance,
so you must try it.
- Zigra's main characteristic?
Of course, he's French.
TOM SERVO:
He's not French, he's Belgian.
- And this time, stay there.
Up you go and don't move.
- Okay now.
- Go on, go.
CROW:
I'll bet.
- Raise the voltage.
TOM SERVO:
Damn it, darn it.
You got your
high beams on, dude.
- Oh, it's working.
I knew it.
CROW:
Now we can project movies
on him.
JOEL:
Spotlight dance on Zigra.
TOM SERVO:
Full reverse, full reverse.
- This is counter-defense
headquarters, come in.
CROW:
This is counterproductive here.
- Please answer.
- Dr. Henry,
Mr. Wallace, please answer.
Please answer.
TOM SERVO:
I'm trying, I'm trying.
- Dr. Henry, Mr. Wallace.
Come in, come in.
Answer please.
- Answer!
Henry!
- Papa! Come in, Papa!
JOEL:
Go to the door and answer
in the form of a question.
- All this is entirely my fault.
I shouldn't
have given that message.
CROW:
She's right. It's her fault.
Let's get her.
- We'll all be eaten
by Zigra sooner or later.
JOEL:
Hey, this isn't really that sad.
[THUNDER AND LIGHTNING]
CROW:
Penitentiary Three.
TOM SERVO:
It was a dark and stormy night.
CROW:
Whoa, Gamera.
You're on the air.
TOM SERVO:
Oh my gosh, I overslept.
I'm gonna miss the bus.
JOEL:
Hawaii Five-0?
Oh.
CROW:
Oh Moon Doggie,
let's get married, Frankie.
JOEL:
I know. It's almost over.
Just hang in there, folks,
come on.
TOM SERVO:
You see, itching, flaking...
I think it's dandruff.
CROW:
Hm.
TOM SERVO:
♪ Why am I alone
With my dark star? ♪
- Uh, Gamera's gone.
- What?
CROW:
[indistinct] got 'em.
- Do you think Gamera
will try to save the Bathyscope?
- Even if he does try,
the oxygen supply
in the Bathyscope
must have given out
over eight hours ago.
CROW:
Yep.
JOEL:
Mommy, make that guy
stop looking at me.
CROW: Heh, heh, heh.
- And he died of suffocation.
TOM SERVO:
Did I get that right,
they died on vacation? Hm.
CROW:
Aw, who cares?
Come on.
[♪♪♪]
- Save them, Gamera,
save them!
- Stay back.
Don't get too close.
JOEL:
Look, I'm not gonna get this
out of the gutter
every time you kids
throw it up there. Okay?
CROW:
Now don't call me
unless you really need me.
Right?
- All right.
Let's get them.
CROW:
Uh, did we miss something?
TOM SERVO:
Uh, is this underwater?
JOEL:
I think.
- Get the stretcher.
Gently, gently!
JOEL:
Looks like a big port-a-potty.
TOM SERVO:
Um. We did miss something.
- Henry, Henry!
- Papa, Papa!
JOEL:
Is there an echo?
- Put them down over here.
CROW:
Put 'em down.
Okay, they're ugly.
Ha, ha.
- Kenny!
- Helen!
TOM SERVO:
George, Heathcliff, McCloud.
- Did they die of suffocation?
- They're dead,
but not by suffocation.
CROW:
Oh that's a relief.
JOEL and TOM SERVO:
Huh?
- I think I know.
The ray has stopped
cellular activity,
so now all the cells
are dormant.
- Then, then
they're not... dead.
JOEL:
No, but they might as well be.
- There's a very good hope
of reviving them.
- Oh!
- Zigra was angered
by what Lora Lee said,
so it sent out its ray...
TOM SERVO:
Huh.
- ...which suspended
organic activity,
and that's the reason
they're not dead.
- Yes, exactly.
TOM SERVO:
So it's a man ray.
- If they had suffocated
from lack of oxygen,
there wouldn't be any way
of reviving them.
JOEL:
So they're only mostly dead.
ZIGRA WOMAN:
No, don't thank me yet.
Thank me
after they've recovered.
- Doctor,
how will you treat them?
TOM SERVO:
Incompetently.
- Electric shocks.
Gamera, don't forget,
was also revived by a series
of light beam shocks.
- That's true.
Sergeant, make preparations
to revive them.
CROW:
And get those cattle
prods out of my trunk...
Oh, I dreamed I ate
[indistinct],
and I'm not [indistinct].
Go figure.
[MONSTER ROARS]
JOEL:
You know, I see
a monster fight coming on;
I can't tell why,
but I just do.
CROW:
Well, look at him.
He looks like
a stealth sturgeon.
[MONSTER ROARS]
CROW:
Come on, come on.
Pick me up.
[MONSTER ROARS]
TOM SERVO:
I'm not the one
that wants to break up.
CROW:
Yeah, yeah.
Well,
I'm keeping all your albums.
TOM SERVO:
Is this your copy
of "Catcher in the Rye"?
CROW:
Come on, give it back to me,
come on.
Nah, keep it.
What do I care?
[MONSTER ROARS]
JOEL:
Plenty of room, come on.
Bring it in.
Come on.
TOM SERVO:
Oo-o-h.
Dishwashing liquid.
CROW:
Gamera's soaking in it.
[MONSTER ROARS]
JOEL:
Nice lines on that monster,
though.
CROW:
All right.
Look at this one.
How about that?
Can you do that?
JOEL:
[indistinct].
You know, Gamera's
never seen the [indistinct].
CROW:
Ah, it shows.
JOEL:
Uh-hm.
CROW:
Gentile.
[LAUGHS]
CROW:
Look, he's on stand-up suit now.
JOEL:
No, I just had my teeth x-rayed,
come on.
TOM SERVO:
Ha, he had jalapenos for lunch.
JOEL:
I guess so.
CROW:
Ooops.
TOM SERVO:
Whoa, he can't take it there.
They can't take it there.
CROW:
Ooops.
TOM SERVO:
Ouch. Zorro, the gay blade.
JOEL:
Hey, Gamera's got stigmata...
oh, I hope
he's not playing hangman.
TOM SERVO:
We could be here a while.
CROW:
Tic-tac-toe.
TOM SERVO:
Whoo-hoo, oops.
[indistinct] Brains
[indistinct], you know.
Whoo-hoo, hoo.
JOEL:
Not again.
CROW:
Oh look.
He's protecting himself
with a zesty tartar sauce.
ALL:
Yuk!
CROW:
Oh, oh.
TOM SERVO:
Pretty exciting now.
Hey, interspecies dating
is not allowed.
CROW:
Listen, if I die,
I'm taking you with me.
- Helen, Helen, Helen,
wake up.
JOEL:
No, are you kidding me?
I was out of the film.
Don't wake me up.
I want a Coke.
- Can I have a Coke?
ALL:
Oh God. You called it.
So predictable.
- Right away.
CROW:
No Coke, Pepsi.
- You're all right now.
JOEL:
Sounds like
an Orange Crush song.
CROW:
♪ Spam spam spam spam ♪
ALL:
♪ Spam spam spam spam
Spam spam ♪
TOM SERVO:
Hey, he's getting a nosebleed.
CROW:
♪ Doot doot doot da-doot ♪
JOEL:
Oh, like a big lawn dart.
CROW:
♪ Gamera ♪
TOM SERVO:
Well, that should
take care of him.
JOEL:
Now wait just a minute.
CROW:
How did he do it?
TOM SERVO:
I don't believe this.
CROW:
This film's getting
a little implausible.
JOEL:
Well, there's
the Howard Johnson's.
TOM SERVO:
Ooo-h.
CROW:
Oh, that, that's Gamera
over there.
JOEL:
You know,
I don't even care anymore
who's killing who.
TOM SERVO:
No.
CROW:
Ho, ho, ho.
That's funny.
That's rich.
I love physical humor.
TOM SERVO:
Nah, I don't find this funny.
I've got a meatball on my nose,
for crying out loud.
CROW:
Does Gamera find this funny?
Does he find it amusing?
Is he some sort of clown?
TOM SERVO:
I guess so.
JOEL:
Oh, now she wants
the Terminator size
cup of Coke.
CROW:
I'm not done yet.
Come here, you.
TOM SERVO:
Oh, well, it looks tonight
the fish will sleep
with Luca Brasi.
CROW:
Hey, get this.
I got a turkey leg
for my breakfast.
JOEL:
Pizaaa!
CROW:
Oh, no.
Oh, please say
this is not happening.
JOEL:
Gamera, known as "Bags"
to his friends.
CROW:
N-B-C.
TOM SERVO:
Rip Taylor on vibes.
CROW: Get this tune?
JOEL: Hey?
Hey, whipping post.
TOM SERVO:
Whooo.
CROW:
Hey, he's doing a strip.
He's gonna take his shell off.
JOEL:
Aw, crack me up.
Bust a move, Gamera.
CROW:
Now he's dancing go-go.
TOM SERVO:
Mammy, Mammy.
CROW:
Oh, oh, oh.
Aw, kill me.
That's the only relief I'd get.
[MONSTER ROARS]
CROW:
Thank you,
good night, everybody.
- Gamera! The flamethrower.
- Fight, fight.
JOEL:
Did he just flame those kids?
I hope so.
TOM SERVO:
Yeah, he did...
Now why couldn't he have
done this in the first place.
Did he forget
he could do this?
CROW:
It would have saved
a little time.
JOEL:
Watch out
for the back draft, guys.
Doesn't he know that open flame
like that is illegal?
CROW:
The horror!
TOM SERVO:
Ordinarily this would
the movie, bu-u-t...
CROW:
This is a Sandy Frank film.
TOM SERVO:
Burned my eyelashes.
JOEL:
Somebody check the grill.
The fish is done.
CROW:
It's blackened, you see.
JOEL:
Hm.
CROW:
Okay, we get the point.
Say...
[MONSTER ROARS]
TOM SERVO:
Now, are you happy?
Next time, don't call me.
I'm supposed to be
laying eggs this time of year.
CROW:
I am [indistinct].
JOEL:
Dad, can we let him crush us?
CHILDREN:
Good-bye Gamera, good-bye.
CROW:
Ooh, ooh.
Uh, uh, we're hideously
burned and scared.
- You're terrific, Gamera.
- Kenny, look at this.
Someone threw it away.
CROW:
The gods must be crazy, Kenny.
- You know, Kenny,
the seas and the oceans
are among
the most precious possessions
that we have on earth.
CROW:
Wait a minute.
She doesn't have a Coke.
She's got a Rolling Rock there.
- ...can threaten
man's very existence.
Our water is sacred.
Gamera taught us that lesson.
If the oceans die,
then mankind will die,
so we have to protect...
CROW:
Boy, Gamera burns
a lot of hydrocarbons
under the ocean.
- Gamera, thank you.
- Thank you, Gamera.
- Gamera, see you soon.
- Good-bye, Gamera.
TOM SERVO:
I don't think you should have
a paunch when you're six.
CHILDREN and CROW:
♪ Gamera Gamera ♪
ALL:
♪ Let's just get it over with ♪
CROW:
♪ I curse the day
Sandy Frank was born! ♪
I was winging it there.
[TOM SERVO HUMMING]
CROW:
♪ Spam spam spam... ♪
JOEL:
Guests of Gamera
stay at the Gamera
and fly Gamera.
CROW:
♪ Spam spam spam ♪
♪ And women of Osaka
Visit Gameraland ♪
TOM SERVO:
Wow, Tokyo Disneyland sucks.
There's Nothingworld
and Parkingworld and Wetworld,
and uh... [indistinct].
CROW:
♪ Gamera ♪
Well, I sure hope Sandy Frank
gets a burial at sea.
JOEL:
Oh, he is a member
of the Neptune Society,
you realize.
CROW:
Oh wait. It's not over yet.
TOM SERVO:
What?
It says the end.
CROW:
I know, but we gotta sit and see
the stupid Sandy Frank
Productions thing.
JOEL:
I don't see any...
CROW:
There, you see what I...
JOEL:
Now it's coming. Good.
TOM SERVO:
Oh boy.
JOEL:
Thanks.
- All right, we finished
the experiment, everybody,
and we feel like singing.
- Hot Patootie.
- Hoi polloi.
- Three-fisted
hot buttered Bob,
and each one of us
has decided
to do our version
of the Gamera theme song
in a separate style.
I've elected to do mine
in the version
of that famous Rastafarian
chart buster, [indistinct].
♪ Ot the Gamera Bunding
Ing bunda ♪
♪ Gamerai ing ing ♪
♪ Oh but the Gamera
Is really neat inga ninga ♪
♪ Gamera is full o' meat
Ding ing ding ing ♪
CROW:
Uh, thank you, Joel.
Say, that was
really, really neat.
- Let's hear it for Joel.
Now, then.
I've chosen a little hipper,
that is to say,
hepper groove
to lay down in.
Campa, make it cool for me.
♪ Life bleeds out into
The Tokyo streets ♪
♪ And Gamera shakes his tail
In a Ginza bistro ♪
♪ With eyes like beta moons ♪
♪ He lights up a skyscraper ♪
♪ Like a Chesterfield ♪
♪ And strolls singing
"Gamera Gamera" ♪
♪ You're a ninja baby
You're [indistinct] ♪
♪ You're about as neat
As a cheap seat ♪
♪ In the midnight peep show ♪
♪ Where all the old men
Are gonna... ♪
- Uh, Tom.
- Oh, sorry.
- Crow, take it.
- ♪ Bustin' moves on monsters ♪
♪ And he fights for good ♪
♪ He's gotta be about the
Biggest turtle in the hood ♪
♪ I said Gamera ♪
♪ He's really neat ♪
♪ I'm talking Gamera ♪
♪ He's uh, really neat ♪
♪ He's filled with meat
And just about ♪
♪ Don't walk behind him ♪
♪ 'Cause when he squats
In the street... ♪
JOEL:
Hey, hey.
Come on, Crow.
You know, being with you guys,
I feel like Dave Seville
with the Chipmunks
or something.
Hey Gypsy, ready?
GYPSY:
No.
- Come on, would you come here,
you.
GYPSY:
Oh, [indistinct].
- I think hers is gonna be
self-evident when she starts.
Okay.
- Oh, Joel.
CROW:
Come on, go ahead.
Like we rehearsed.
- ♪ Gamera oh oh ha ♪
♪ [indistinct] he's the best ♪
CROW:
Uh-huh.
GYPSY:
♪ Uh huh ha ho ho ha ha ha ♪
ROBOTS:
Oh, beautiful.
JOEL:
All right. Bravo. Good show.
You did all right.
Okay, and we've decided then
to do a really nice version,
all together.
[HUMMING]
ALL:
♪ Gamera is really neat ♪
♪ Gamera is full of meat ♪
♪ We all love you Gamera ♪
- We think so.
It's pretty sweet, huh?
- I don't think so,
Milli Vanilli.
- One, two, three, four.
♪ Gamera is really neat
Gamera is really neat ♪
[indistinct]
- Uh, huh, hey, I think
we broke the control panel.
Ah, eh.
[♪♪♪]
- Big shot.
Just who does he think he is?
A hotel manager indeed.
I showed him.
Huh?